craneandcanopy.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy | Crane & Canopy

TO UNSUBSCRIBE (EMAIL OR DIRECT MAIL)

You can easily remove yourself from our direct marketing efforts here: UNSUBSCRIBE

You can also send us an email at [customerservice@craneandcanopy.com](mailto:customerservice@craneandcanopy.com) with your email and/or your address to be removed from our lists.

OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Here at Crane and Canopy, we are committed to respecting your privacy and recognizing your need for appropriate protection and management of contact information you share with us. “Contact information" is any information by which you can be contacted or personally identified, such as your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number and more.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of:

  * what information we may collect from you
  * how we use such information
  * the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to review, correct and opt out of our use of the information.

This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect about you through our website. By using our website or sharing your contact information with us, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. As part of our commitment to your privacy, we will provide customers with notice of their ability to opt out of information rental, sale or exchange with other marketers, honor customers' requests not to share their contact information with other marketers and honor customers' requests not to receive mail, telephone or other solicitations from Crane and Canopy, Inc. Brands.

COLLECTING INFORMATION

There may be times (such as when you purchase or order a product, subscribe to a service, register to receive catalogs, or to participate in contests, sweepstakes or promotions, etc.) when we ask you to provide certain contact information about yourself. This may include your name, shipping and billing address, telephone number, email address, social media user name, credit card information, birth date, gender, occupation, personal interests and more. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases.

Whether or not to provide such information is completely your own choice. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you may be unable to purchase products, or access certain services, offers and content on our website. In addition, we may need to contact you via phone, email or mail to address questions or issues specific to your order, entry and more, even if you have opted to not receive marketing communications from us.

You can generally visit many of our web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any contact information about yourself. We may track the Internet domain address from which people visit us, other electronic markers and identifiers and other information about our site. We may analyze this data for preferences, trends, site usage statistics and to recognize you. We may also receive usage data from your mobile phone or other device you use to access our website, including location data, which we may also combine with other information.

We may collect your email address via cookies and pixels on the Website through the use of trusted third party partners.  These partners may also combine your email information with other information they have access to such as mailing address so that we may serve relevant marketing offers to you via email and direct mail.   If you do not want us to collect information about you, please remove yourself from our direct marketing efforts here: UNSUBSCRIBE

If you access any of our websites or mobile applications with your log-in credentials from a social networking site or if you otherwise agree to associate your account with us with a social networking site, we may receive personal information about you from such social networking site, in accordance with the terms of use and privacy policy of the social networking site. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our stores, websites and mobile applications.

USING INFORMATION

We use your contact information for marketing and analytics purposes, such as:

  * confirming and tracking your order or registration
  * analyzing preferences, trends and statistics
  * informing you of our new products, services and offers
  * providing you with other information from and about Crane and Canopy, Inc. Brands.

We contact you only in ways compatible with your communications choices. To the extent necessary for such purposes, we take reasonable steps to make sure that your contact information is accurate, complete, current and reliable.

We might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom we believe trustworthy and whom we have asked to confirm that their privacy policies are consistent with ours. These are known as Select Partners. In such cases we might rent, exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including contact information about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online or through our catalogs. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with others, including providers of third party cookie and other third party browsing and use data. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize the shopping experience of you and others with us, and to recognize our customers so that we can communicate with you directly about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes. We may share contact information and other data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with any Crane and Canopy, Inc. Brands.

We may contract with companies or persons to provide certain services, including credit card processing, shipping, data analysis and management, promotional services and more. We call them our Service Providers. We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services. We also ask our Service Providers to confirm that their privacy practices are consistent with ours.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and collect certain information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other website in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third-party web beacon to collect this information. Our systems do not recognize "Do Not Track" signals, but several of these third-party companies who utilize these cookies or beacons on our website enable you to opt out of this behavioral advertising. To learn more or opt out from these companies you can visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/. We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us or certain transfers of your information. You can learn about this in the "Opting Out of Marketing and Transfers" section of this Privacy Policy.

In certain instances, we may disclose your contact information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, Crane and Canopy, Inc. Brands or others. We may also disclose your contact information when we believe the law or legal process requires it.

Opting Out Of Marketing; Updating Information

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to receive direct marketing from us or from our Select and/or Service partners, or if you would like to opt out of our rental or exchange of your information with other marketers, please let us know. You can easily remove yourself from our direct marketing efforts HERE.  You can call us at 888.686.8586 or send us an email at [customerservice@craneandcanopy.com](mailto:customerservice@craneandcanopy.com). Please be sure to include your full name, email address, mailing address and specifically what information you do not want to receive. You may also click the designated unsubscribe link at the bottom of all emails from us to be removed from future emails. Please note that any requests to remove or update your contact information may take up to five days for your email request and 6–8 weeks to process your postal mail request.

To Opt out of online advertising programs, go [HERE](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

Using Cookies

When you visit our website, we send one or more cookies to your computer or other device. We may also use cookies in emails that you receive from us. A cookie is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a website. A session cookie expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A persistent cookie stores information on the hard drive, so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date the cookie information is still available. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service when you visit our website and other websites of interest. We also use cookies to remind us of who you are, tailor our products, services and advertising to suit the personal interests of you and others, estimate our audience size, assist our online merchants to track visits and sales at our website, promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and to process your order and more.

Service Providers may use cookies and collect information on our behalf. They are prohibited by our contract with them from sharing that information with anyone other than us or our other Service Providers. However, we respect your right to choose whether to be included in such services. In addition, we or certain of our Service Providers may work with third parties who use cookies to collect information to tailor advertising for you and others elsewhere on the Internet and on our website, and to assist in reminding us of who you are. If you would like to opt out of accepting cookies altogether, you can set your browser to not accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. However, certain features of our website or other services may not work if you delete or disable cookies.

Keeping Your Personal Information Secure

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of information transmitted to us. To guard your information delivered to us electronically, our website uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL encrypts your credit card number, name and address so only we can decode your information. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your contact information, to the extent permitted by law, we do not guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our website, and you do so at your own risk. As a result, to ensure that others cannot access your account, especially if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place, we urge you to keep any password that you establish with us in a safe place and not to divulge it to anyone, log off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit.

Protecting Children

Crane and Canopy, Inc. Brands take special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. Our website is a general audience site. We do not permit anyone under the age of 13 to register with us and not send email correspondence to anyone who tells us that they are under the age of 13. We urge parents and guardians to participate in their children's online activities and use parental control or other web filtering technology to supervise children's access to the Internet.

If you believe we may have inadvertently collected such information from your child, please notify us immediately by sending an email to [customerservice@craneandcanopy.com](mailto:customerservice@craneandcanopy.com) or calling us at 888.686.8586.

Accessing Our Site From Outside The U.S.

If you are visiting our site from a location outside of the United States, you will be connected through and to servers located within the United States. All online orders will be accepted and fully processed in and shipped from the United States and all information you provide will be securely maintained on web servers and our internal systems located within the United States. By providing your information to us, you agree that all personal information will be used in accordance with this privacy policy and pursuant to U.S. law.

Linking to Third-Party Websites

For your convenience and information, our website and emails may contain links to other sites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the content or practices of any linked site. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of any site that you access through our Website.

Posting Information To Public Forums

If you use a bulletin board, chat room or any other interactive or publicly accessible area, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected or used by any person for any purpose. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable or other information you choose to submit in these forums.

Updating Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the bottom of this policy, and in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy when you interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. Your continued use of our web sites or other services constitutes your acceptance of the practices described in the revised Privacy Policy.

Leaving Your Feedback

For questions about our Privacy Policy, to make choices about receiving promotional communications, to update your personal information or to place an order, you can call us at 888.686.8586 or send us an email at [customerservice@craneandcanopy.com](mailto:customerservice@craneandcanopy.com).

Effective Date: March 2018
